bodum.com 2017-09-11

# BODUM® - Privacy Policy

## **Data Privacy Statement**

The following statement, together with our Terms and Conditions, and any other documents referred to in them, informs you of the type, scope and purpose of our processing activities with regards to the personal data which we may collect from you or which you provide to us.

## **1\. Responsible office**

The office responsible for collecting, processing and using your data is

Bodum AG

Kantonsstr. 100

CH - 6234 Triengen

Register No.: CH-100.3.004.758-3.

## **2\. Collection, processing and use of personal data**

**2.1 Personal data**

Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. This includes your name, telephone number, address and all inventory data that you provide to us while registering and creating your customer account.

**2.2 Customer account**

For each customer who registers an account, we set up password-protected, direct access to that customer’s saved inventory data (customer account). Here you can review data about your completed, open and recently submitted orders and manage your address data and newsletter preferences. You can also send out wish lists through your customer account, and rate products.

**2.3 Collection, processing and use of your data**

You can visit our website without providing personal information. In this case, we will only collect access data, such as the name of your internet service provider, the page from which you are visiting us, the browser type/version/language, and a few other pieces of technical information or the name of the file you requested. This data is technically required in order for us to provide our offering and is used solely to administer our website.

When you order a product, we will collect, save and process your data for the complete processing and billing of your purchase. For your order, we will need your correct name, address and payment data. We need your email address in order to confirm your order and to communicate with you. We also use it for identification (customer login). In addition, you will receive your order and shipment confirmation through your email address.

With your permission, we will also use your personal information for the purpose of sending out promotional materials for our own products, such as our newsletter, by email and by mail. You can prevent your personal information from being used for promotions by clicking [her](mailto:privacy-opt-out@rhapsody.com)e. Each of our newsletters naturally also includes an unsubscribe link.

Your personal data will only be shared with third parties or otherwise transmitted if this is necessary in order to execute the contract or for billing purposes, or if you agreed to this in advance. During order processing, for instance, the service providers we use here (such as carriers, logistics specialists and banks) receive the data necessary for processing the order and executing the contract. Data shared in this manner may only be used by our service providers to fulfill your assignment. Any other use of the information is not permissible, and does not occur with any of the service providers we hire.

Your personal data will be deleted – as long as statutory storage requirements do not oppose this and if you assert a deletion claim – once the data is no longer required to fulfill the purpose for which the data was stored or if for statutory reasons it is no longer permissible to store the data.

## **3\. Cookies**

Visiting our web pages does not require you to accept cookies. However, please note that you can only use the shopping cart feature and place orders for products if you allow us to set cookies.

**3.1 What are cookies?**

Cookies are small files that are saved on your data carrier that store certain settings and files regarding the exchange with our system through your browser.

**3.2 Which cookies does Bodum use?**

**3.2.1 Session Cookies**

Most of the cookies that are used by us are session cookies. These are cookies that we use to remember your log in details and what you have added to your basket. These are necessary to ensuring the website functions correctly and that you can make purchases.

**3.2.2 Permanent Cookies**

In addition we also use temporary/permanent cookies that are saved on your data carrier for a longer period of time or permanently. These cookies help us to adapt our web pages and offerings specifically for you, and they make it easier for you to use the site, for instance by saving certain entries you make so that you do not need to constantly re-enter the information.

**3.2.3 Affiliate-Cookies**

Moreover, we use „Affiliate-Cookies“. These cookies show us how you found our website and which website you came from. This helps us to know which of our online marketing channels is most effective. They also allow us to reward some external websites for directing you to us.

**3.2.4 Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies,” text files which are stored on your computer to enable analysis of website usage by you. Information generated by the cookie about your use of this website (including your IP address) is transmitted to a Google server in the United States and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, compile reports about website activities, and provide the website’s operator with further services related to website and Internet usage. In addition, Google may share this information with third parties where required by law or if third parties process the data on behalf of Google. Under no circumstance will Google link your IP address with other data from Google. You can prevent storage of cookies by appropriately setting your browser software; in this case, however, please note that you might not be able to fully use all functions offered by this website. Furthermore, you can prevent data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) from being recorded and sent to Google, along with the processing of this data by Google, by downloading and installing the browser plugin under the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>. You can prevent recording by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set that blocks future recording of your data when you visit this website: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>. More information about the terms of use and data privacy can be found at <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html> and at <https://www.google.com/intl/en-us/+/policy/content/.html>.

**3.2.5 Google AdWords**

This website uses Google AdWords Conversion Tracking, a web analysis service of Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google AdWords Conversion Tracking also uses cookies, which are stored on your computer and facilitate an analysis of how you use the website. These cookies become ineffective after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If you visit specific pages of our website, we can track whether you were forwarded to that page by clicking on an ad. If you do not want to participate in the tracking you can deactivate cookies for conversion tracking by setting your browser so that cookies of the [www.googleadservices.com](http://www.googleadservices.com/) domain are blocked.

**3.3 How can I block cookies from being saved?**

If you want to block the use of all or some specific cookies, you can change the settings in your web browser to remove all previously saved cookies and prevent new cookies from being saved. More information is available on your browser’s Help pages. The following links explain the procedure for some common browsers:

Please note that removing or blocking cookies may mean that you cannot use Bodum’s offerings, or that your use of these offerings will be limited. For instance, your default settings may not be recognized, and some of our pages may not be fully displayed.

Where can I find more information about cookies?

More information about cookies and how you can block the use of cookies can be found on the following third-party websites:

## **4\. Social Plugins**

We use plugins from social networks on our website. You can identify the plugins by the respective network logo. The plugin informs the social network that you called up the corresponding page of our website. If you are logged in to the social network, the network can assign this visit to your account. If you interact with the plugins, for instance by clicking on the Facebook “Like” button or adding a comment, the corresponding information will be transmitted by your browser directly to the social network and saved there.

For more on the purpose and scope of data collection and the further processing and use of the data by social networks, as well as your rights and setting options in this regard in order to protect your privacy, please see the data privacy notices of the respective networks and/or websites.

If you do not want social networks to gather data about you through our website, you will need to log out of these networks before visiting our site.

Even if you are not logged in to the social networks, websites with social plugins can send data to the networks. Each time the website is called up, a plugin sets a cookie with a code. Since your browser sends this cookie without being requested each time there is a connection to a network server, the network could in theory create a profile of which websites the user assigned to the code has called up. It would then certainly be possible to assign this code back to a person, for instance when the person logs in to the social network later.

If you do not want social networks to gather data about you through plugins, you can select the “[Block third-party cookies](https://support.mozilla.org/de/kb/Cookies-von-Drittanbietern-blockieren)” feature in your browser settings. The browser will then not send cookies to the server for embedded content from other providers. However, this setting may in some cases also prevent cross-page functions from working in addition to the plugins.

## **5\. Secure data transmission**

We securely transmit your personal data using encryption. This applies to your order as well as to the customer login. We use the SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encoding system. While no one can guarantee absolute protection, we use technical and organizational measures to secure our web pages and other systems to prevent the loss, destruction, access, modification or distribution of your data by unauthorized persons.

## **6\. Informational rights of affected parties**

Our customers have the right to obtain information about their stored data, as well as the right to correct, block or delete data if applicable.

We take protecting your data very seriously. In order to ensure that personal data is not shared with third parties, please direct any email inquiries to [privacy@bodum.com](mailto:privacy@bodum.com) and identify yourself clearly.

## **7\. Changes to this policy**

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
